Lesson 9  A School Day
学校のある一日
わたしの学校では、生徒は制服を着なければなりません。
At my school, students have to wear a uniform.
毎朝、時間どおりに教室にいなければなりません。
Every morning, we have to be in the classroom on time.
授業では、数学、理科、英語など多くの教科を学びます。
In class, they have to study many subjects:
math, science, and English.
家に帰ると、夕食前に宿題を終えなければなりません。
When I get home, I have to finish
my homework before dinner.
妹は時々、「全部今夜中に終えなければならないの？」と聞きます。
My sister sometimes asks,
“Do you have to finish all of it tonight?”
「うん、そうだよ」と、わたしは答えます。
“Yes, I do,” I answer.
日曜日は学校へ行かなくてよいですが、家で皿を洗わなければなりません。
On Sunday, I do not have to go to school,
but I have to wash the dishes at home.
時には大変ですが、家族を助けることはとても大切です。
It is sometimes hard,
but helping my family is very important.